Inventory of the H. H. Kung papers, 1917-1949
Hoover Institution Archives
H. H. Kung papers, 1917-1949
1919-1949
2006C51
Hoover Institution Archives
107 manuscript boxes, 3 oversize boxes (49.5 linear feet)
Speeches and writings, correspondence, reports, conference proceedings, meeting minutes, and audiovisual material, relating to political and economic conditions in China and to Chinese diplomatic policy and finances during World War II.
Kung, H.H. (Hsiang-hsi), 1880-1967
Access
51 of the 110 boxes in this collection are open for research as of January 19, 2010. Due to the fragility of the original documents, only microfilm copies (68 reels) will be provided for researchers' use.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Related Materials
Kia-ngau Chang papers, 1889-1979, Hoover Institution Archives
Chiang Kai-shek diaries, 1917-1972, Hoover Institution Archives
T. V. Soong papers, 1916-2005, Hoover Institution Archives
Zhongguo guo min dang records, 1894-1957, Hoover Institution Archives
Biographical/Historical Note
1881 Born, Shanxi Province, China
1896-1900 Studied at North China Union College in Tongzhou
1906 Graduated from Oberlin College, Ohio
1907 Graduated from Yale University, M.A. in Economics
1913 Secretary of the Chinese YMCA, in Tokyo, Japan
1914 Married Soong Ailing
1924 Joined the Kuomintang (KMT)
1925 Received honorary LL.D. degree from Oberlin College
1928 Named Minister of Industry and Commerce
1929 Elected to the KMT Central Executive Committee
1932 Appointed special commissioner to study European industrial conditions, assigned to secure foreign aid for the development of China's national defense
1933 Governor, Bank of China Minister of Finance Vice-Premier, Executive Yuan
1937 Represented the Chinese National Government as special envoy during the coronation of King George VI Received honorary degree from Yale University
1938-1939 Premier, Executive Yuan President, Chinese-American Institute of Cultural Relations
1948 Moved to New York, United States
1967 August 15 Died, Long Island, New York
Scope and Content of Collection
The Hoover Institution received on deposit, 103 boxes of H. H. Kung papers in 2006. Of this material, contents of 51 boxes are available for research. Due to the fragility of the original documents, only microfilm copies will be provided for researchers' use. This finding aid describes the papers in these 51 boxes. A microfilm reel list, which indicates corresponding box and reel numbers, is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
The other boxes are closed due to the hazardous physical condition of the papers. A significant portion of the papers suffered mold infestation, and displayed other signs of deterioration when received at the Hoover Archives.
The microfilmed Kung papers at Hoover bear witness to and describe turning points of the Republic China era, such as the passing of Sun Yatsen in 1925, the Manchurian Incident of 1931, the Xi'an Incident of 1936, the Second Sino-Japanese War (1937-1945), the Chinese Civil War (1946-1949), and the reformation of China's modern banking and monetary system.
Among the previously less-known historical accounts now revealed from Kung's personal papers are Nationalist China's endeavors to manufacture its own military weapons before and during World War II, intelligence reports concerning the Chinese Communist Party's financial, economic, and military operations in the Shaaxi-Gansu-Ningxi Border Region, Japanese secret activities in China in the early war years, and the intricate relationship between Chiang Kai-shek's central government and regional warlords and political factions.
A major component of the collection includes KMT records, conference proceedings, meeting minutes, agendas, reports, resolutions, and other support documents from the Central Executive Committee and the Supreme National Defense Commission (bulk 1930-1943). The collection also includes core domestic and foreign policy making files compiled during Kung's political career as Minister of Industry and Commerce, Minister of Finance, and Premier of the Executive Yuan.
The papers also exhibit Kung's charitable and educational endeavors such as his involvement in disaster relief efforts and the establishment of the Oberlin Shansi Ming Hsien School (see English correspondence files, 1917-1948) which fostered cross-cultural and education exchange programs.
Arrangement
The arrangement of this material reflects the original order of the papers when received from the donors.
Kung, H.H. (Hsiang-hsi), 1880-1967; China--Economic conditions--1912-1949.; China--Politics and government--1912-1949.; Finance, Public--China.; Statesmen--China.; World War, 1939-1945--China.; World War, 1939-1945--Diplomatic history.; World War, 1939-1945--Economic aspects.
- Aircraft manufacturing for warplanes, 1933-1942 (Reel 1, Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes correspondence, price quotations, and aircraft description and specifications from aircraft manufacturing companies.
  - Aircraft standards and regulations, 1938 (Reel 1, Folder 1: 1)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1942 (Reel 1, Folder 1: 2-4)
  - Far-East Aviation Co., Ltd, 1933 (Reel 1, Folder 1: 5)
  - Koolhoven Aeroplanes, 1938 (Reel 1, Folder 1: 6)
- Real estate files, 1928 (Reel 1, Folder 1: 7-11)
- Printed matter, 1929 (Reel 1, Folder 1: 12)
- China Child Welfare Inc., 1929-1931 (Reel 2, Folder 1: 13)
- David Kung, undated (Reel 2, Folder 1: 14)
- Sino-Japanese relations, 1932-1937 (Reel 2, Folder 2: 1-10)
- Manchurian (Mukden) Incident, 1931 (Reel 2, Folder 2: 11)
- Xi'an Incident, 1936-1937 (Reel 3, Folder 2: 12-13)
- Zhang Xueliang correspondence file, circa 1931 (Reel 3, Folder 3: 1)
- Yan Xishan and Feng Yuxiang correspondence file, 1936-1937 (Reel 3, Folder 3: 2-5)
- Shanxi file, 1circa 1930-1931 (Reel 3-4, Folder 3: 6-8)
- Chinese Communists, 1939-1946 (Reel 4, Folder 3: 9)
- Chinese Communists, 1939-1946 (Reel 4, Folder 4: 1-7)
- Wang Jingwei and Hu Hanmin correspondence file, 1935-1938 (Reel 4-5, Folder 4: 8-11)
- Sun Yatsen Mausoleum Construction Committee, 1925 (Reel 5, Folder 5: 1-2)
- Sun Yatsen Funeral Services Committee, in Chinese, circa 1925-1930 (Reel 5-6, Folder 5: 3-11)
- Digest of translated and transcribed news reports, records, telegrams, correspondence, meeting minutes, undated (Reel 6, Folder 5: 12)
- Digest of translated and transcribed news reports, records, telegrams, correspondence, meeting minutes, undated (Reel 7, Folder 6: 1-5)
- Digest of translated and transcribed news reports, records, telegrams, correspondence, meeting minutes, undated (Reel 8, Folder 7: 1-2)
- English correspondence files, 1917-1945 (Reel 8, Folder 7: 3-10)
- English correspondence files, 1917-1948 (Reel 9, Folder 8: 1-6)
- William Hunt and company, 1941-1945 (Reel 9, Folder 8: 7)
- Aviation, 1941-1944 (Reel 9, Folder 8: 8)
- Aerial transportation, 1941-1944 (Reel 9, Folder 8: 9)
- China Foundation, 1940-1941 (Reel 9, Folder 8: 10)
- KP Chen (Chen Guangfu), 1941 (Reel 9, Folder 9: 1)
- Appointment applications received, 1944 (Reel 9, Folder 9: 2)
- Foreign Ministry, 1941 (Reel 10, Folder 9: 3)
- Chinese embassy, London, 1941 (Reel 10, Folder 9: 4)
- Chinese government Trading Commission, 1941 (Reel 10, Folder 9: 5)
- East-West Association, 1945 (Reel 10, Folder 9: 6)
- Customs administration, general, 1943 (Reel 10, Folder 9: 7)
- Foreign Exchange Central Commission (application for Foreign Exchange), 1941 (Reel 10, Folder 9: 8)
- French Embassy, 1941 (Reel 10, Folder 9: 9)
- Export Import Bank Cotton and Wheat Loan, 1939 (Reel 10, Folder 9: 10)
- Intelligence reports, circa 1935-1940 (Reel 11-13, Folder 10: 1-14)
- Intelligence reports, circa 1935-1940 (Reel 13-14, Folder 11: 1-11)
- Intelligence reports, circa 1935-1940 (Reel 14-16, Folder 12: 1-10)
- Shanghai municipal government intelligence reports, 1932 (Reel 16, Folder 13: 1)
- International relations, 1938 (Reel 16, Folder 13: 2)
- Finance and banking, 1924-1934 (Reel 16, Folder 13: 3-4)
- Miscellaneous documents, 1934-1938 (Reel 16, Folder 13: 5)
- Provincial policy address, undated (Reel 16-17, Folder 13: 6-10)
- Intelligence reports, circa 1938-1939 (Reel 18-19, Folder 14: 1-10)
- Intelligence reports, circa 1938-1939 (Reel 19-21, Folder 15: 1-10)
- Ministry of Industry, 1931
  - Mining, 1931 (Reel 21, Folder 16: 1-3)
  - Agriculture, 1931 (Reel 22, Folder 16: 4-5)
  - Water, 1931 (Reel 22, Folder 16: 6)
- Ministry of Commerce, 1925-1928 (Reel 22-23, Folder 17: 1-3)
- Central Bank files, 1944 (Reel 23, Folder 17: 4-6)
- Headquarters of Four Joint Banks, 1944 (Reel 23, Folder 17: 7)
- Farmer's Bank of China, 1944 (Reel 24, Folder 17: 8)
- Aviation, 1944 (Reel 24, Folder 17: 9)
- Central Trust, 1944 (Reel 24, Folder 17: 10)
- Tax regulations, undated (Reel 24-25, Folder 18: 1-8)
- Four Banks (Central Bank, Bank of Communications, Bank of China, Agricultural Bank) joint meeting, circa 1943 (Reel 26-27, Folder 19: 1-3)
- Disaster relief, circa 1933-1935 (Reel 27-28, Folder 20: 1-4)
- Foreign affairs, national defense and political affairs, 1934-1936 (Reel 28, Folder 20: 5-7)
- Economic Committee, undated (Reel 28-29, Folder 21: 1-6)
  Consists of the records of various several subcommittees, including the establishment of fundamental industrial and commercial units, reorganization of domestic and foreign loans, wartime financial policies, the stabilization of the Foreign Exchange Market in Shanghai and natural resources.
- Economic Committee, undated (Reel 29, Folder 22: 1-4)
- Confucius Temple, circa 1928-1935 (Reel 29, Folder 22: 5-10)
- Sun Yatsen funeral records, 1925 (Reel 30, Folder 23: 1-4)
- Sun Yatsen funeral records, 1925 (Reel 30, Folder 24: 1-6)
- Sun Yatsen funeral records, 1925 (Reel 31-32, Folder 25: 1-6)
- KMT Party Affairs Report, 1936 (Reel 33, Folder 26: 1)
- Central Executive Committee, 1929 (Reel 33, Folder 26: 2-4)
- Central Executive Committee, 1941 (Reel 34, Folder 26: 6-8)
- Central Executive Committee, 1941 (Reel 35, Folder 27: 1-2)
- Central Executive Committee, 1929 (Reel 35, Folder 27: 3-4)
- Central Executive Committee, 1930 (Reel 35-36, Folder 27: 5-8)
- Central Executive Committee, 1931 (Reel 36, Folder 27: 9-12)
- Zong Li (Sun Yatsen) Memorial Committee, 1929-1931 (Reel 36-37, Folder 28: 1-9)
- Party Affairs Report, 1929 (Reel 38, Folder 29: 1)
- Central Executive Committee, 1930 (Reel 38, Folder 29: 2-3)
- Central Executive Committee, 1931 (Reel 39, Folder 29: 4)
- Central Executive Committee, 1932 (Reel 39, Folder 29: 5)
- Central Executive Committee, 1935 (Reel 39, Folder 29: 6)
- Central Executive Committee, 1936 (Reel 39, Folder 29: 7)
- Central Executive Committee, 1939 (Reel 39, Folder 29: 8-12)
- KMT National Congress Meeting Minutes, 1924 (Reel 39, Folder 30: 1)
- KMT National Congress Meeting Minutes, 1926 (Reel 39-40, Folder 30: 2-4)
- KMT National Congress Meeting Minutes, 1929 (Reel 40-41, Folder 30: 5-7)
- KMT Central Executive Committee, 1929 (Reel 41, Folder 30: 8)
- KMT National Party Congress, 1931 (Reel 41, Folder 30: 9)
- KMT Central Executive Committee, 1931 (Reel 41, Folder 30: 10-12)
- KMT Central Executive Committee, 1929 (Reel 41, Folder 31: 1-3)
- KMT Central Executive Committee, 1930 (Reel 41, Folder 31: 4)
- KMT Central Executive Committee, 1931 (Reel 41, Folder 31: 5-8)
- National Party Congress, undated (Reel 41-42, Folder 31: 9-20)
- Central Executive Committee, 1940 (Reel 42, Folder 32: 1)
- Central Standing Committee, 1938 (Reel 42, Folder 32: 2-3)
- Central Executive Committee, 1930 (Reel 43, Folder 32: 4)
- Central Standing Committee, undated (Reel 43, Folder 32: 5)
- Central Executive Committee, 1938 (Reel 43, Folder 32: 6-7)
- Central Executive Committee, 1940 (Reel 43-44, Folder 32: 8-10)
- Central Executive Committee, 1939 (Reel 44, Folder 32: 11)
- Central Executive Committee, 1935 (Reel 44, Folder 32: 12)
- Central Executive Committee, 1939 (Reel 44, Folder 32: 13)
- Central Executive Committee, 1938-1940 (Reel 44, Folder 32: 14)
- Central Executive Committee, 1940 (Reel 44, Folder 32: 15)
- Central Executive Committee, 1937 (Reel 44, Folder 32: 16)
- Central Executive Committee, 1940-1941 (Reel 44, Folder 33: 1-14)
- Central Executive Committee, 1935 (Reel 45, Folder 34: 1-4)
- KMT Political Council, 1927 (Reel 45, Folder 34: 5-15)
- KMT Political Council, 1927 (Reel 46, Folder 35: 1-6)
- Central Executive Committee, 1927-1931 (Reel 46, Folder 35: 7-15)
- Central Bank, 1936 (Reel 46, Folder 35: 16-21)
- Ministry of Finance, 1936 (Reel 46-47, Folder 35: 22-26)
- Executive Yuan, 1942 (Reel 47, Folder 36: 1)
- Executive Yuan, 1943 (Reel 47, Folder 36: 2-3)
- Ministry of Transportation, 1940 (Reel 47, Folder 36: 4)
- National Assembly, 1931 (Reel 48-49, Folder 37: 1-24)
- National Assembly, 1931 (Reel 49, Folder 38: 1-6)
- National Assembly, undated (Reel 49, Folder 38: 7-10)
- National Supreme Defense Council, 1938 (Reel 50, Folder 38: 11-12)
- National Supreme Defense Council, 1939 (Reel 50, Folder 38: 13)
- National Supreme Defense Council, 1940 (Reel 50, Folder 38: 14)
- National Supreme Defense Council, 1939-1940 (Reel 50-51, Folder 39: 1-13)
- National Supreme Defence Council, 1939-1940 (Reel 51-52, Folder 40: 1-18)
- National Government State Council, 1928-1931 (Reel 52-53, Folder 41: 1-28)
- State Affairs Conference, laws and regulations, 1928-1931 (Reel 53-54, Folder 42: 1-16)
- State Affairs Conference, miscellaneous documents, 1928-1931 (Reel 54, Folder 42: 17-20)
- State Affairs Conference, miscellaneous documents, 1928-1931 (Reel 54-55, Folder 43: 1-9)
- Executive Yuan, state affairs, circa 1928-193 (Reel 55, Folder 43: 10-24)
- Executive Yuan, circa 1930 (Reel 56, Folder 44: 1-10)
- Wartime Finance Committee, circa 1936-1937 (Reel 56-57, Folder 44: 11-20)
  Includes resolutions, meeting minutes, correspondence, and other supporting documents relating to wartime finance.
- Currency policy, taxation System, and currency management, undated (Reel 57-58, Folder 45: 1-6)
- Executive Yuan meetings, circa 1935-1936 (Reel 58-59, Folder 45: 7-12)
- Executive Yuan meetings, circa 1936-1940 (Reel 59-60, Folder 46: 1-14)
- National Mobilization records, circa 1943 (Reel 61-62, Folder 47: 1-3)
- Executive Yuan meetings, circa 1943 (Reel 62-63, Folder 48: 1-4)
- Executive Yuan, circa 1943 (Reel 64-65, Folder 49: 1-3)
- Ministry of Finance, circa 1927-1928 (Reel 65, Folder 49: 4)
- Executive Yuan meetings, circa 1930 (Reel 65-66, Folder 50: 1-4)
- Executive Yuan meetings, circa 1931 (Reel 66, Folder 50: 5-7)
- Executive Yuan meetings, circa 1938 (Reel 66, Folder 50: 8)
- Executive Yuan meetings, circa 1943 (Reel 66-67, Folder 50: 9-10)
- Executive Yuan meetings, circa 1930 (Reel 67-68, Folder 51: 1-9)
- Executive Yuan meetings, circa 1931 (Reel 68, Folder 51: 10-13)
- Executive Yuan meetings, circa 1940 (Reel 68, Folder 51: 14)
- Executive Yuan meetings, circa 1941 (Reel 68, Folder 51: 15-17)
- Executive Yuan meetings, circa 1943 (Reel 68, Folder 51: 18)